DMITRIY KHAILOV

Frontend Developer
https://t.me/h4x0rlol • dmitriykkh@gmail.com • h4x0rlol.me • Russia, Saint Petersburg

Skills

Frontend:

JavaScript · TypeScript · React · React · Native · Next.js · Redux (Toolkit, RTK Query) · Mobx (State-Tree) · Apollo · Websockets · REST · GraphQL · WebRTC · SCSS · CSS Modules · Styled Components · Material-UI · TailwindCSS · Jest · KotlinJS · Telegraf

 $Tools: ESLint \cdot Style lint \cdot CommitLint \cdot Prettier \cdot Husky \cdot Webpack \cdot Vite \cdot Git \cdot Github \cdot Gitlab \cdot Jira \cdot Trello \cdot Slack \cdot Linux \cdot Bash$

Experience

BeetSoft

Frontend Developer 07/2021 - 12/2021

Web development

- Development of the client side of cross-platform mobile applications on React Native, MobX, GraphQL.
- Optimized application performance on weak devices by formalizing the state in the application and reducing data cohesion, as well as using approaches for list virtualization and memoization of calculations.
- Added a real-time state update in the application.
- Reduced the frequency of crashes on certain types of devices by selecting compatible versions of libraries.
- Initiated the implementation of the retrospective process in the team.
- SPA development on React (Redux Toolkit, REST, GraphQL).

NetSyde

Frontend Developer 10/2019 - 06/2021

Web3 development team

Part-time

- Development and support of decentralized applications (dApp).
- Development of a public API for a decentralized freelance exchange based on the Waves blockchain.
- Simplification of the testing process by writing specialized utilities.
- One of the authors of the distribution algorithm in the decentralized financial distribution system on the Binance Smart Chain blockchain.
- Development of Telegram bots.
- Fulfillment of third-party orders.

Education

Omsk State Transport University

Master in Information systems and technologies (Information systems development technologies)

09/2022 - Ongoing

Omsk State Transport University

Bachelor in Software Engineering (Informatics and Computing)

09/2018 - 06/2022

• Was engaged in the development of an online store for the sale of English courses for children "Happy Hearts" using the Yandex Kassa API.

Developed client-server projects using Kotlin (Kotlin.js, ktor).

Was a member of the jury at the regional programming competition "Hot Keys" from the center of additional education "Makhaon".

Open Source

- An open source service for deployment on a local network that allows users to interact in a real-time session with a virtual canvas for drawing, also with real-time chat support to increase the productivity of work meetings, thereby reducing their time and increasing labor productivity.
- Dashboard for monitoring indoor air parameters using Raspberry Pi, as well as displaying data from various public APIs.
- A simple peer-to-peer chat based on WebRTC on random topics.
- -Multiplayer darts game in the form of a telegram bot.
- Application for tracking weather conditions anywhere in the world using maps.

About me

I also sometimes write technical notes on the blog (for example, how to properly configure certain hardware for Linux or assemble the Dashboard mentioned above on a microcontroller and sensors).

I take a great interest in functional programming (but I do not try to drag in prod) and mathematics.
I have a contribution to large Open Source repositories, such as React.

More details on the Open Source projects I've worked on can be found here:

https://www.h4x0rlol.me/

My github account:

https://github.com/h4x0rlol